The last model we'll introduce here are recurrent neural networks,
最后要介绍的一种模型是循环神经网络
which are used in natural language processing as well as time series.
它可以用于自然语言处理和时序运算
Recurrent neural networks are as the name implies neural networks.
顾名思义 循环神经网络是一种神经网络
Neural networks are models that can be thought of as
神经网络是指很多回归
many regressions stacked in series and in parallel.
按序列并行堆叠起来的模型
When I say the regressions are in a series,
回归按序列堆叠是指
I mean that the output of one regression is fed
一个回归的输出
in as the input to another regression in a chain.
作为输入传入另一个回归中 像链条一样
Also, when I say parallel,
并行堆叠是指
I mean that there are multiple regressions
有很多个回归
whose outputs are fed into another layer of regressions.
这些回归的输出会传入另一个回归层级
A recurrent neural network is called recurrent because it takes some of
循环神经网络中的循环一词是指
its intermediate output and uses this as
在用传入的数据进行训练时
part of its input as it trains itself on incoming data.
它将部分中间输出当做输入
The recurrent neural network takes an input and outputs in prediction.
RNN 会接受输入并输出预测值
The recurrent neural network also outputs an additional signal
RNN 还会输出其他信号
and intermediate output which it feeds back into itself.
即中间输出 并将该信号传入其本身
At the next time step when the RNN receives another input from the data source,
在下个时间步 当 RNN 从数据源中获得另一个输入时
it uses both the input as well as
它会同时使用该输入
its previous intermediate output to help it calculate its next prediction.
以及上一个中间输出计算下个预测值
You can think of this signal as a way for
可以将这种信号看做
the RNN to remember relevant information from the past.
RNN 记住过去的相关信息的一种方式
To train a recurrent neural network,
为了训练循环神经网络
you feed it lots of data from the past,
你需要传入很多过去的数据
then you see how well it predicts data from the future using
然后使用梯度下降法
a process called gradient descent to adjust the coefficients in the network.
来调整网络的系数 最后就可以看到 RNN 预测未来数据的效果了
One commonly used version of recurrent neural network is made
一种常见的循环神经网络形式
up of one or more long short-term memory cells.
由一个或多个长短记忆单元组成
The long short-term memory cell,
长短记忆 (LSTM) 单元
or LSTM cell consists of several neural networks each that perform a specific task.
由多个神经网络组成 每个都负责特定的任务
The LSTM cell can be thought of as an assembly line,
LSTM 单元可以看做一个装配线
and specific tasks are performed by different assembly line workers.
不同的装配线工人负责特定的任务
The LSTM cell takes data as input and also
LSTM 单元将数据作为输入
takes its own signals that it generated from the previous period.
并且将上个时期生成的信号也作为输入
The signal that it takes from its previous period
从上个时期获取的信息
can be thought of as its memory from the past.
可以看做过去的记忆
Some of the assembly line workers, remove some memories.
某些工人会消除某些记忆
Other assembly line workers add more memories based on incoming data.
其他工人根据传入数据添加更多记忆
Still other assembly line workers decide what to output.
还有一些其他工人决定输出什么
Remember that the recurrent neural network has two kinds of outputs.
循环神经网络有两种输出
One, is its prediction for the variable in question.
一种是对相关变量的预测
The other is an intermediate output for its future self.
另一种是关于未来本身的中间输出
You can think of this intermediate output as
可以将中间输出看做
the memory that it wishes to pass on to the next time period.
它希望传递给下个时期的记忆